Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Amen.
You may be seated. Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Hallelujah.
I was trying to be jealous of you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I was telling God, "Please, Baba God, release me!
I want to dance! I want to join them!"
Thank you.
Viewers all over the world, I want to thank you for your time.
God's time is the best.
If you do things at God's time, you will astonish yourself,
you will surprise yourself.
Just wait for God's time.
I remember that I left you on a message 'Talk on Faith'.
Talk on Faith.
That is it.
There is no substitute for faith.
There is no what?
There is no exchange for faith.
There is no substitute for faith.
Faith's value is unique - so unique.
Let's quickly talk about that.
Halleluyah.
Open the book of James 2.
Look at verse 18.
"But someone will say, 'You have faith; I have deeds'."
That is work.
"Show me your faith without deeds..."
It means, faith and your work, and the work of faith.
"...and I will show you my faith by my deeds."
By my actions.
"You believe that there is one God."
That is the statement there.
"You believe that there is one God. Good!"
There is a talk there.
"You foolish person, do you want evidence that faith without deeds is useless?"
That is evidence.
"Was not our father Abraham considered righteous for what he did
when he offered his son Isaac on the altar?"
Verse 22.
"You see that his faith and his actions were working together,
and his faith was made complete by what he did."
That is father Abraham.
Talk on faith.
Halleluyah.
We are faced with God's uncompromising demands for faith.
You can see that there is an issue here.
The righteous shall live by faith.
Whatever is not from faith is sin.
Without faith, it is impossible to please God.
This is why I call it, uncompromising demands for faith.
He who comes to God must believe and have faith.
There is no substitute.
They are Divine demands.
Its values are unique.
There is no substitute for faith - no alternative, no shortcuts.
This is why we are Christians.
The Bible says faith must be confessed with the mouth
but this faith confession must proceed from genuine faith in our hearts.
It must proceed from where?
From genuine faith in our hearts.
Why?
That shows that there all kinds of faith - faith in stones, faith in this, faith in that,
faith in faith, faith in yourself.
In the world, they use the word faith in business.
"I have faith in that business." - This is misusing the word.
Faith is a trust.
You can only trust God and love everyone.
You cannot trust human beings; they will leave you one day.
Faith is a trust but we use it as a misused word - all kinds of faith.
We are guilty of using empty words.
Today, we are guilty of using empty words. That is, an empty profession of faith.
You see people say, "Yes! In the name of Jesus!"
An empty profession of faith will not help us in any way.
It's like talking to the air.
"In Jesus name!" is going nowhere; it's in the air; it is an empty profession of faith.
Faith confession must be backed up by appropriate action.
That is faith without what?
I mean, faith without an appropriate action is dead.
Faith confession must be backed up by appropriate action.
What do I mean?
Let me just give you a picture of what I'm talking about.
If I say, I believe God will heal me and I'm at the same time worried and distressed,
my faith is questionable.
I say, I believe God will heal me. God will deliver me. God will bless me.
Like many of us are sitting down now.
After you finished dancing, you are now falling into your self-pity again.
But when you were dancing, you were happy.
After that now, you start thinking, "Ah, the thing is paining me again.
The thing is hitting me again".
Is it dancing that removed it?
No!
You believe God will heal you; you believe God will bless you and save you
and you are at the same time worried and distressed -
that nullifies your faith - question mark.
If you have faith in God, you should not just believe in Him.
That is the idea today: Everybody believes in God, that is why you are here today.
Look at the picture.
Faith is like children to their father.
Not only should we know God as our Sovereign Lord,
we should know Him like children know their father.
You know your father.
Good children; good father.
You say, "Daddy!"
You know the time to ask daddy what you want.
You know the time not to ask daddy, and you know the time to greet daddy.
Today, you don't know the time to ask God what you want; that is why you ask wrongly.
You don't know the time to come to God.
You don't know what God has in store for you.
The Bible says we must know God's will and pray according to His will.
But you don't know God's will; you only pray.
You don't know whether what you are asking is God's desire to give you.
You don't know.
You pray but you never know God's will concerning what you are asking for.
Whether it is the time to give you what you are asking for.
Whether that is exactly what He has in mind to give to you.
And whether it is the right time to give it to you. But you don't know, you just pray.
"In Jesus' name! In Jesus' name! Amen!"
That is why you always have disappointment - you pray, no answer.
You don't know when to pray, how to pray and what to ask for. You don't know.
Faith is like good children, loving children to their loving father.
That is faith.
The picture of belief is like a farmer saying, "I believe God is able to give me a harvest
without planting any seed".
"I believe God will give me, God is able to give me a harvest" - that is a farmer.
I am giving you a picture of belief without faith.
Many of us as believers today, we do not know how to believe, and express our faith. That is the problem.
We do not know how to believe and express our faith.
You don't know; that is believers today.
We believers, we do not know how to believe and express our faith.
Faith is expressed through work.
By work, faith is perfected.
If I say, "I believe it will not rain" and at the same time, I carry an umbrella along,
that is a question mark.
That has nullified your faith.
What does that mean?
It means you have not yet had faith.
Because when our hearts are uneasy and worried, this shows that we have not yet had faith.
That's when you are going and you say, "I believe it will not rain".
Now carrying an umbrella shows that you are worried.
There's a kind of worry in your heart.
That is why you have to carry an umbrella along.
I believe it will not rain. But now I'm going to carry an umbrella along.
That shows there is a kind of worry.
How should one have faith?
That is the question.
We have faith through the daily things around us.
I will not say through the happenings around us - I limited it.
I want to limit it this way - through the daily things around us.
My head, my shoulders, my knees, my toes, they all belong to God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You have just forgotten that.
Can you, on your seats, sing along with me?
My head, my shoulders, my knees, my toes
They all belong to Jesus
Faith is manifested in the small things.
When you want to sit - "In the name of Jesus!"
It means you believe in God to sit.
You want to stand - "In Jesus' name!"
You believe in Jesus to stand, you believe you cannot stand without Jesus.
You must know how much you need God to have faith.
Tell your neighbour.
I can't hear you.
You must know how much you need God to have faith.
Today, we don't know how much we need God.
You don't know, you believe you can sit on your own.
There are many things you believe you can do on your own.
How many of you have called the name of Jesus before combing your hair?
Before you begin to dress up, how many of you say, "In Jesus' name!"?
When you are about to see, will you call the name Jesus to see?
You want to eat, will you call the name of Jesus to eat?
Faith is manifested in the small things in our daily lives.
For you to have faith in God, that faith we are talking about,
you must know how much you need God.
That's why I take you to shoulder, head, toes.
Total dependence upon Him - you are not totally dependent on God
because there are many things you do on your own.
Those are things satan uses to hit you.
Each time satan wants to attack you, he goes through those things you do on your own.
You know you can sit on your own, you don't need to invite Jesus,
you don't need to bring Jesus to the scene before you sit.
Many people today that are just about to sit have strokes.
They collapse.
You need to know how much you need Jesus to have faith in Him -
in things both great and small.
Not mine not mine
The choice
In things both great and small
Be Thou my Guide my strength
My wisdom my all
That's all.
This is where your problem comes from: You don't know how much you need God.
You don't know how much you need God.
That is why you have a time for prayer.
All time is for prayer, not a time for prayer.
If you knew how much you needed God - total dependence on Him to smile, to drink,
to look, to turn your neck - you would pray 24/7.
To greet, you need God to do that.
That is why you cannot have faith.
Faith is not a part-time Christianity; it is full-time.
If we cannot commit our bodies to God when we are sick and troubled,
who will believe you have faith?
Who will believe? - Only the foolish.
If you cannot trust in God in your sicknesses, afflictions, situations and tribulations,
when will you trust him?
Tell your neighbour.
If you cannot trust in God in your trouble, tribulation, situation, temptation,
when will you trust in Him?
MESSAGE TITLE: TALK ON FAITH | PART 4
There are many troubles people carry to me.
You would see them after the prayer, they would carry their medication to see me,
"Man of God, this is my drug".
Some would meet me and say, "Will I still be using my medicine after the prayer?"
If you cannot trust in God with your medicine, you cannot trust in God without your medicine
because God Himself is the God of nature.
Those medicines are derived from nature - plants.
If a farmer can trust nature without a definite promise,
we Christians should trust the God of nature.
God is God of nature.
For an operation to be sucessful, God makes it successful.
For one to have a good treatment, God makes it thus.
He opens the way for a successful operation; He opens the way for a successful treatment.
We treat; God heals.
Doctors treat; God heals.
MESSAGE TITLE: TALK ON FAITH | PART 4
He opens the way for a successful operation,
for a successful treatment.
He opens doctors' eyes to give you appropriate treatment - the rightful treatment.
He opens their eyes.
If not, they'd not see anything, they'd not even know how to go about it.
Tablets and medicine are nature and God is God of nature.
If you cannot trust in God with your medicine, you cannot trust in Him without your medicine.
God bless you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service